lolsided.com 2019-11-04

# LolSided

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, feel free to contact us.

**Data Controller.**  
The controller of personal data is Wayne Whitty, who owns and operates LolSided.com. Wayne Whitty is based in the Republic of Ireland. If you wish to make a query about our personal data processing or if you wish to obtain information on the processing of your personal data, please use one of the contact options on our contact page. 

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our app?**  
We do not keep a long-term record of personally identifiable information. Our app is built in such a way that storing your Facebook information in a database would be completely unnecessary. If you have taken any of our quizzes in the past, then you can rest assured that we have not kept a database record of any of your personally identifiable information.  
The only reason we would ever keep a record of your personally identifiable information is if we believe that your account activity is abnormal or you are suspected of violating our Terms of Service. 

**Third-party disclosure.**  
We do **NOT** sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. If you agree to provide us with access to your name, gender, etc, that information remains with LolSided.com and it is never transferred to a third-party.  

**Temporary PII storage.**  
Any personally identifiable information that is saved on our server is saved in a temporary session file that is automatically expired and removed within an hour of your session expiring.  
To manually expire your session, you can click on the "Log Out" button in the top right-hand corner of our app.  
If you forget to click on the "Log Out" button, your session data will be automatically expired and removed from our server after a short period of time.  
If we cache your profile picture for performance reasons, that profile picture is saved and named in such a way that it is not linked to the rest of your personal information.  
If we do cache your profile picture, it is for the sole intention of speeding up the time that it takes us to provide you with a quiz result.  
If you do not share any of our results, cached profile pictures are automatically removed from our server within an hour after they have first been cached.  
If you do share one of our results, your cached profile picture may be stored for roughly 45 days. This image is stored in such a way that it is not linked to your name or the rest of your personally identifiable information.  
In certain cases, LolSided.com may log Facebook IDs, IP addresses or names for the purpose of generating statistics and identifying user behavior. These log files are temporary and are automatically deleted by our servers after a couple of days.  
In the vast majority of cases, this data is automatically removed and compiled into non-identifying aggregate data every 60 seconds.  

**How do we use your information?**  
We use your information to provide you with personalized Facebook results. Example: By giving us access to your basic Facebook public profile information, you give us the ability to generate personalized quiz results that include your name, profile picture and gender-related pronouns. 

**Facebook permissions.**  
Our app abides by the Platform Policy for Facebook developers. Our app does not make any unnecessary requests for Facebook permissions. We only request data and permissions that our app requires to generate results.  
In most cases, we only ask for your basic profile information: This includes your Facebook profile ID, name, profile picture and gender.  
On quizzes that involve a member of your friend list, we will ask for the friend list permission.  
We do **NOT** ask for access to your interests, likes, timeline posts, photo albums or messages.  
For more information on what Facebook information we request, please see our article on Facebook Permissions. 

**Do we use cookies?**  
Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember if you are logged into LolSided.com or not. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. 

**We use cookies to:**  

  * Check if you are logged into LolSided.com or not.
  * Keep track of advertisements.
  * Keep track of saved preferences.
  * Keep track of what quiz you are taking.
  * Distribute traffic amongst our load balancers / servers.
  * Keep track of your "App-scoped" Facebook ID, which is unique to LolSided.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic, Facebook shares and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services such as Google Analytics and Facebook Analytics that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You can do this through your browser (like Chrome or Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. 

**If users disable cookies in their browser:**  
If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled. It will turn off some of the features that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. 

**Third-party links.**  
Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites. 

**Google.**  
Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. Please see: [AdWords policies](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en)

**We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.**  
Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

We have implemented the following: 

  * Remarketing with Google AdSense
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting
  * Demographics and Interests Reporting
  * DoubleClick Platform Integration

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.  
For more information, see Google's article on [How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). 

**Opting out.**  
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on. 

**Transfer Of Data.**  
Your information, including personal data, may be transferred to - and maintained on - computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.  
Our servers are situated in the United States of America.  
If you are located outside of the United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including personal data, to the United States and process it there.  
Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.  
LolSided will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information. 

**Legal Requirements.**  
LolSided may disclose your personal data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:  

  * To comply with a legal obligation.
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of LolSided.com.
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with LolSided.
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the service or the public.
  * To protect against legal liability.

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act).**  
We do not specifically market to children under 13. 

**How do we protect visitor information?**  
We use secure server software (SSL) to encrypt information that is sent between your browser and our website.  
The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

**Fair Information Practices.**  
The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information. 

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:

We will publish a notice on our website and on our Facebook page within 2 business working days.

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors. 

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, you can contact the website.

Last Edited on 17 Sep 2018 

* * *
